ASGHAR ABBAS

Correspondence Address- 352A, Gali Number-18, Khadda Colony, Jaitpur Ext Part-2, New Delhi-110044

Permanent Address- 87/B, Ajmeri, Hammam Darwaza Near Hanuman Mandir, Sadar, Jaunpur, Uttar Pradesh- 222001 Contact Detail- +91-7827080823 Email- abbas.asghar22@gmail.com

RESEARCH OBJECTIVES

To work for an organization that provides me the opportunity to improve my skills and knowledge to grow along with the organization's objective by means of Research, planning and implementation or rationalized strategies at the grass root and thereafter at management level for the betterment of the marginalized population within the existing resources and prevailing conditions.

PROFILE

Research scholar with approx nine years of rich experience in Public Health, Health Research, Qualitative and Quantitative Research Studies, Documentation and Communication and life science while working under competent, experienced and dignified Principle Investigators, Senior Research Officer's, Professors and Project Head. Studied several different areas of public health and Qualitative and Quantitative Research methods.

- Productive independent researcher with excellent communication & team skills
- Can interact effectively with hospital and population-based study.
- Experience managing research groups/projects.

RELATED RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

My past research experiences have been varied in their methodologies and areas of study. As my research interests have become more focused, I am increasingly aware that the breadth of my experiences helps me think flexibly about research questions, hypotheses, and study design. My first exposure to research, as in MS biotechnology, was at the cancer biology at Indian Academy of biotechnology. Although my research career has just begun, I have accumulated a strong background in several research fields and have developed a strong research foundation that will help to ensure my future success as a research scholar. Over the last (9 Years) nine years, I have gained research experience in the three main areas of public health, Qualitative and Quantitative Research, Documentation and Communication and Life Science: field research, Qualitative and Quantitative study and techniques, and data collections-based research with many national or international organizations like IIHMR-New Delhi, Jhpiego, FHI360, TISS-Mumbai, IIHMRU-Jaipur etc. Also 3 years working experience with one of the projects of DST. The project entitled "Climate Change and malaria in sub Himalayan region and Central India (ICMR-NIMR-DST)".

MAJOR TASK

- Monitor progress toward project objectives, including facilitating strategic planning and compile the needed documentation.
- Develop protocol, with direction provided by the principle investigators, to test research hypothesis and process or outcome evaluation measures.
- Contribute significantly to the success of project.
- Produce periodical project report, Data analysis and report writing, Proposal Development etc.
- Evaluate the project specific technologies, project and study results, products and processes.

Any other activity assigned by the Project Directors & senior Research officer from time to time.

ADDITIONAL RESPONSIBILITY

- Establish report and maintain public relation with local community and enlist the cooperation of the community especially Panchayat leaders, School teachers etc.
- Qualitative data collection through FGDs (focus group discussion) and In-depth interview and sampling.
- Coordinate with the volunteers in the community organizations and applying innovative methods. Coordinate with team and analysis and reporting of data.
- Supervision of field-based workers on project intervention.

EMPLOYMENT

- Worked as a Research Officer with International Institute of Health Management and Research, New Delhi from 24th/February/2012 to 22nd/March/2017
- Worked as consultant with FHI360, New Delhi from 17th/June/2017 to 28th/January/2018
- Worked as Research Assistant with TATA Institute of Social Science, Mumbai from 2nd/June/2018 to 15/March/2019
- Worked as Research Officer with IIHMR University, Jaipur. From 15th/July/2019 to 31st/March/2020.
- Working as Programme Associate with REACH TB Network, New Delhi. From 1st/April/2020 to 30th/ September/2020.

TRAINING AND WORKSHOPS

- Workshop attended on "Research Ethics "organized by FHI 360 North Carolina USA
- Workshop attended on Post-Partum family Planning Integration MCHIP JHPIEGO
- Training attended on Cancer Prevention and Palliative care by Tobacco Advocacy (Cancer Aid Society, Lucknow)
- Research and Communication Skills for early Career Public Health Researchers (Welcome trust DBT- INDIA ALLIANCE)

INTERNSHIP

- Volunteer (Tobacco Control) internship at Cancer Aid Society
- Climate Change and malaria in sub Himalayan region and Central India (Main Study-ICMR-NIMR- DST)

EDUCATION

S.N.	Examination	Year	Division	Percentage	Board/University
1	10 th (Science)	<u>2001</u>	2^{nd}	<u>49.8%</u>	<u>Uttar Pradesh Board</u>
2	<u>12th</u>	<u>2004</u>	1 st	63.2%	Uttar Pradesh Board
<u>3</u>	<u>B.Sc</u>	<u>2009</u>	2 nd	<u>58.88%</u>	Ranchi University, Ranchi
4	M.Sc	<u>2011</u>	1 st	<u>69.3%</u>	Vinayka Mission University, Tamilnadu
<u>5</u>	MPH (Master's in Public Health)	<u>2021</u>	1 st	72.00%	Indian School of Technology and Management, Mumbai
<u>6</u>	DMS (Doctorate in Management Studies)			Appeared	Indian School of Technology and Management, Mumbai

ACADEMIC AND PROFESSIONAL PROJECT'S AND DESSERTATIONS

- Types of cancer and their definitions. (**Indian Academy of Biotechnology**)
- Testing and validation of strategies of urban health initiatives to increase contraceptive prevalence in Uttar Pradesh. (UHI-FHI360- 2012 to 2013)
- Let Girl be born (**Plan India- 2013**)
- Situation analysis and need Assessment of MON district- (Plan India)
- Landscape Analysis for misoprostol and other Uterotonics in India: An exploratory study (**PSI-2014**)
- The Cigarettes and Other Tobacco Products Act (COTPA): Compliance Assessment Survey In 3 Districts in India (COTPA-2014)
- A Qualitative Research to Understand the Perceived Opportunities and Barriers
 For Prevention and Management of Diabetes and HBP Among General
 Population in Sonepat District Of Haryana (PHFI- 2014)
- Child and maternal Health (**DFID-UK-2014**)
- Climate Change and malaria in sub Himalayan region and Central India (**Pilot study-ICMR-NIMR-DST**)
- Descriptive Evaluation of Postpartum Family Planning Integration Models in India (JHPIEGO)
- Climate Change and malaria in sub Himalayan region and Central India (Main Study-ICMR-NIMR- DST)
- Review of MIS in social protection (Save the children and MGNREGA)
- Geospatial Mapping of Diabetes, CVD and Cancer Risk Hotspots and Study of Risk Assessment (Department of Science and Technology)
- Review and Evaluation of M-Tobacco Cessation Program in India (WHO)
- Micro-Needle patch acceptance in India- (FHI360-US)
- Identifying changing trends in Sex Work Dynamics Among Female Sex Workers in India- (TISS, FHI360, NACO)
- Vaccine Hesitancy and Social Determination of Child Immunization; with focus of Social Groups and Network (SIHFW and UNICEF)
- Supporting NHM in Developing Capacities of Health Care Staff on Improvement of WASH in Health Centers and NRC's Madhya Pradesh Project (UNICEF, IIHMR University WASH)-2019
- ALLIES Project, The Accountability of Leadership by Local Community for Inclusive, Enabling Service "ALLIES" Initiatives Funded by **USAID**

PUBLICATIONS

- Current scenario of Breast Cancer in rural of India and Genological Impact (Scientific India Magazine)
- Genetic of eye color: No single gene responsible for eye color, (Article published in IIHMR newsletter)
- Impact of sentiment factor on the Cancer Patient and their Family in Bihar (Scientific India Magazine Social Issues, 13 Mar 2018)

STRENGTH

- Good communication skill
- Team spirit and positive attitude
- Quick and faster

COMPUTER PROFICIRENCY

- MS-office (Word, Excel, Access, PPT, PageMaker, Photoshop etc.).
- Knowledge of statistical software in medical and public health research SPSS, Atlas ti etc.
- STATA
- ODK and KOBO collect application for data collection.

SKIL AND COMPITANCY

- Honesty in all undertaking works
- Communicable and Non-Communicable Disease.
- Communication skills (verbal & written)
- Strong work ethic, Teamwork skills, Initiative, Interpersonal skills
- Problem-solving skills, Analytical skills, Flexibility/adaptability
- Computer and Technical skills
- R&D Biotechnology and public health Qualitative and Quantitative Research
- Designing and Conducting Training Monitoring and value addition
- Documentation, Communication and Data Analysis

PERSONAL DETAIL

Father's Name - Hasan Abbas Mother's Name - Late Itrat Fatema

Nationality - Indian Sex - Male

Date of Birth - 02/May/1985
Category - General
Marital Status - Married
Religion - Muslim
Cast - Shia

Permanent Address -87/B, Near Hanuman Mandir, Hammam Darwazza, Sadar,

Jaunpur, Uttar Pradesh-222001

Hobby -Study books, search for new things, play cricket etc.

Language known: -English (Read, Write, Speak)

-Hindi (Read, Write, Speak) -Urdu (Read, Write, Speak)

MEMBARSHIP OF SCIENTIFIC/SOCIETIES/OTHER PROFESSIONAL BODIES

- The Biotech Research Society
- All India Biotech Association
- Biotechnology Society of India
- Cancer Aid Society
- Cancer Research Society, Delhi
- IEA Cancer Research and NCD Control Society, Jaunpur, Uttar Pradesh

STRONG QUALITY

- Motivation and curiosity, or a passionate interest in something worthwhile,
- Established study or work habits,
- Determination or persistence, not giving up easily,
- Character, or moral sensitivity,
- Honesty and self-respect.

REFRENCES

Dr. K.P. Mishra

Head of the Department Dept of Zoology (Ranchi University) Phone- 9334722310

Dr. Bal Nagorao Rakshase

Associate Professor, Tata Institute of Social Science, Mumbai Campus Phone- 9226322182, Email- bal.rakshase@tiss.edu

Dr. Preetha GS

Associate Professor, IIHMR New Delhi Phone- 9871112107, Email- preethags@iihmr.org

Dr. Manish Priydarshi

Associate Professor, IIHMR New Delhi Phone- 9810348678, Email-manish@iihmr.org

Dr. Sumant K. Swain

Assistant Professor, IIHMR New Delhi Phone- 9868740469, Email- sumant@iihmr.org

Declaration- I hereby affirm that the above information given by me is true to the best of my knowledge and belief. I will solely be responsible for any discrepancy found in them thanking you

A	ASGHAR ABBAS								
	/	A	sgr		ヽノ	All	-		

Date____